[Music]
so this is my second haagen-dazs belgian
chocolate ice cream the first one i made
was an eggless version and actually it
was incredibly close so so close
actually i couldn't really taste any
difference but some people said that
because it wasn't a custard ice cream
can i make the custard version so i've
had to go here spoiler
it's not as good
[Music]
let's start by adding 250 milliliters of
milk to a pan and then add in your 100
grams of sugar and 40 grams of dextrose
now if you don't have dextrose it's
quite easy to buy in most shops actually
now but if you don't you can just sub
that just for straight table sugar it'll
have a slightly different effect on
scoop but it will still be delicious
give it a little stir and then add in
your egg yolks these are uk medium egg
yolks if that makes any difference to
you as i know the eggs are different
sizes all around the world
at around 50 degrees centigrade add in
your cocoa powder and continue to heat
until it reaches 77 degrees centigrade
or thereabouts that's just to make sure
that the eggs are cooked you don't have
to cook the eggs if your eggs are
pasteurized
but it helps with the consistency of a
custard base
turn off the heat and add in the 40
grams of 70 chocolate and stir it well
to make sure it's fully melted
now you can decant into your favorite
container add in 200 milliliters of
double or heavy cream stir it well and
then slam it in the fridge for a few
hours
it's at this point you should take your
add in chocolate and place it in the
freezer as it will be much easier to
chop it later on
when the base is chilled put it in your
machine and churn for 15 to 30 minutes
until it reaches soft serve consistency
whilst it's churning chop up your add in
chocolate as fine as you can get it if
you've got a grater that will work then
use that but if not just keep on
chopping
right at the end of your churn add that
chocolate into the machine and let it
incorporate well
finally load up your tub admire the
belgian chocolate image and wing it in
the freezer for a few hours
[Music]
it's been one in the freezer we're gonna
open it and scoop it and see what it
turned out like
[Music]
it's got a good scoop it's got a good
consistency good texture you can see the
little chunks of belgian chocolate in
there
now i i've not probably cut this belgian
or chopped this belgian chocolate up
enough compared to the previous one i
probably should have spent a bit more
time made it a bit smaller and then it
would have looked a bit more like the
haagen-dazs version but they've got this
massive machine and all chopstick chops
and chopstick
just
chop it however you can and get it in
there make an ice cream at home
it is about science to a certain degree
but it doesn't have to be about science
you can just make ice cream and make it
taste good
now a lot of people on youtube
i'm not claiming i'm an expert in
anything
but i make a lot of ice cream a lot of
people on youtube they make ice cream in
their machines and they take it out of
the machine while it's basically liquid
still and they'll pour it into their
container
and
really what you're doing then is you're
just allowing large ice crystals to form
as it's freezing you're not going to be
left with a really creamy good textured
ice cream a lot will have to do with the
recipe itself but when you're churning
in a machine
you'll know
that it's ready to scoop if you don't
have a digital thermometer or a laser
thermometer like i do
when it keeps its body when you put a
spoon in there and you take some out and
it keeps its shape then you know you're
ready to take it out your machine
if you've got any other questions about
making ice cream i will attempt to
answer them
pop them in the comments below and i'll
ever go either in the comments or i'll
even make a video about all the common
questions that people have about making
ice cream it's not difficult it really
isn't difficult some people make it
difficult
but let's just get stuck in and try this
custard-based haagen-dazs belgian
chocolate ice cream
[Music]
it's really good
now it's different
it's different to the first one i made
a few reasons
one is the type of cocoa powder
this one i've made with
caliber
cocoa powder it's 24 fat
the previous one i made with seven hills
cocoa powder which is only 11 percent
fat it's got a totally different taste
obviously the fact that there's egg
yolks in this one as well the whole
ratio of everything is different
and the first one actually is much
closer than this one this is still an
excellent ice cream and you really won't
go wrong with a good belgian chocolate
ice cream like this but
does it taste just like the haagen-dazs
version no it doesn't
the eggless one
i'll put a link in in the description
for the original belgian chocolate that
is the better more accurate version of
haagen-dazs belgian chocolate
so not quite as successful as the first
attempt at it but hopefully you've
enjoyed watching it all the same
next week we've got another exciting
video coming for you it's one using an
ingredient i've never tried before so uh
keep an eye out for that one it'll be an
interesting one
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
you